[♪ opening theme song playing]
[HANA] Here. Food and clothes.
You can't be dressed like that.
These'll help you blend in.
[YURU] Hmm.
Is this some kind of tunic?
[HANA] Uh, yeah, sure.
And think of this as a hakama.
[DERA] Here, these too.
You'll need something
for your feet.
[HANA] Oh, the small time
Yakuza look suits you.
[YURU] And what are these?
Oh, come on.
Surely you've had onigiri.
[YURU] A hundred percent rice?
No millet?
There's even seaweed?
Are you showing me
the luxuries of this world?
[sighs] Yeah, I guess those
would be luxuries to you.
And how am I meant
to open this container?
Uh?
♪
There.
[Yuru exclaims]
[Yuru screams] Whoa!
How is it so delicious?
Did the gods give you this?
So, you really like it? Here!
-You should have some more!
-[Yuru moans]
Why are you acting
like his grandma?
I wish Asa could eat this
with me.
She'd love it.
-[RIGHT] Oy, Dera.
-[DERA] Hm?
What is this place?
[DERA] Oh, uh,
we call these things rest stops.
It's like a modern day
relay station.
They've got food
and latrines inside.
Could even get a souvenir,
-if it suits you.
-[BOTH] Uh?
[both grunt]
You wanna see? We can.
Nay, Dera.
We stay beside our master.
Why don't you two
have a meal
and handle your bodily
essentials?
We will see to it that
Yuru comes to no harm.
In that case,
don't mind if we do.
-What you think? Ready to eat?
-[HANA] Hm.
Hey. No touching
the wheel, got it?
What of the horses?
Do they not need to be fed?
No worries. I fed them earlier.
♪
[HANA] So, how much
did you tell him?
Well, when I told him
the girl in the keep
wasn't his real sister,
he didn't take it well,
so I thought
I'd leave it there for now.
Didn't wanna throw more at him
than he could handle at once.
You're too nice sometimes.
You gotta remember,
-he's still just a kid.
-[sighs]
Whatever, I hate children,
so I wouldn't know.
Appreciate you buying me
some grub.
So, where are we
bringing the boy?
You gonna make the poor kid
hang out with you at su casa?
Nah, I compromised my name
and face
during that rescue mission.
I'll need a new pad.
I'm ditching that one.
You're homeless and looking
after someone else's kid.
Your life sounds rough.
[Dera grunts, sighs]
This is your life too,
I'm afraid.
As a Higashi Village retainer,
you'll be expected to help me
deal with this.
Sure.
You know I'll do what I can,
but you know...
Great. Then let's get married,
'kay?
[HANA] Got your wedding rings
right here!
Good grief.
Are those in your pocket
everywhere you go?
[HANA] You got
another thing comin'
if you think
I'd ever marry you!
[Dera shushes]
I don't mean a real marriage!
But look, if we wanna
protect Yuru,
we're gonna have to find ways
to blend into the crowd.
Rumors about outsiders
spread like wildfire
in the countryside,
so we'll have to stay
in a populated city.
I just don't know
if I can protect him
from so many threats alone!
We don't need to get married
for me to help keep him safe!
Why can't we be roommates?
Landlords are looking more
to rent to families.
It just sounds a bit more stable
than roommates, I guess.
Yeah, okay!
Then how about I'm his sister,
and we justify
the age difference
by saying you had me
as a teenager?
You could be
a cool single father
who's just trying his best!
[DERA] And in this scene,
did my wife just dump me
and leave me with the kids?
[WOMAN 1] I heard his wife ran.
[WOMAN 2] Oh, man.
Do you think he cheated?
He seems scary.
[DERA] Oh! Maybe I'm a hero,
putting on a brave face
for the children
after his wife
tragically passed.
[WOMAN 3] Such a sad story.
[WOMAN 4] I can't even imagine.
Let's check in and see
if he needs any help.
Either way, I'm gonna get
more attention
than I can handle
on a mission like this.
Think of the rumors!
So Yuru's from my first wife,
and then I remarried younger.
A May-December thing.
There! Glad it's settled.
Thanks for understanding.
[HANA] I haven't agreed
to nothin'.
So which one of us should take
the other one's last name?
-What do you think?
-[Hana grunts angrily]
[HANA] This sucks!
My heart only belongs
to one man,
and that's Jason Statham!
[echoes]
[Right grunts]
[RIGHT]
Where do they keep the horses
inside this tiny box?
Modern craft has come far
in the past 400 years.
Oh, no! Please, forgive
my impudence.
I just realized
I ate all the food myself
and didn't remember
to save any for you.
Our master has the kindest
of hearts, does he not?
Pay us no mind.
We do not require
human sustenance.
[YURU] So, uh,
if it's all right to ask,
what should I call you?
[RIGHT] It's up to you.
You may even give us new names.
[YURU] Hmm.
So perhaps, Lord Right.
And I guess Lady Left?
That sounds so uptight!
Don't concern yourself
with such formality.
We're your daemons after all.
Understood. [grunts]
-Right.
-[Right chuckles]
[YURU] Left.
Let's not mince words.
I want you to tell me
everything you know
about me and my sister.
[LEFT AND RIGHT] Hm?
♪
[RIGHT] Don't get your hopes up.
We sat unmoving in the village
for some 400 years.
Our knowledge
of the goings-on outside
is no more greater than yours.
We only saw the people
who came and went.
We don't even know much
of what happened
inside the village.
At one point, locals spoke
of how twins had been born.
We started seeing
our future master
shortly thereafter.
When you were
little more than a pup,
I recall your father
would oft take you
deep into the mountains
to go hunting.
Yeah.
The very first memories
I have are of him
teaching me about hunting.
Back in those days, though,
we saw neither hide
nor hair of your sister.
We feared the worst.
That perhaps she had been
taken by an illness
not long after she was
brought unto this world.
Until ten years ago...
♪
[LEFT] In the dead of night,
we saw your parents
flee the village
with a young girl in tow.
She seemed small for her age
and her blood smelled as yours.
And that once little girl
grew up much bigger
and laid waste to our village.
All these years, I thought
our parents left me and Asa
with no one to care for us
but each other.
[vehicle passing]
[YURU] But I was the only one
they left.
[Yuru grunts]
Well, all right then.
I'll find this supposed
"real" Asa.
I want to talk to our parents,
and she maybe knows
where they are.
Yeah.
Yeah!
Thanks for waiting.
What's wrong?
Is something bothering you,
Hana?
Because reasons, we're gonna be
your guardians going forward.
Isn't that grand?
Guardians?
We're responsible
if you ever get in trouble,
-so don't get in trouble!
-By the way,
we're probably gonna be
on the road for a while.
Need to use the latrine
before we go?
[YURU] No. I went over there.
[HANA] He's already
getting in trouble!
Also, you're gonna
draw attention
sitting there like a punk.
Get off of the car.
[YURU] I didn't realize.
Is it not a problem
that Right and Left
are up there, too?
Daemons are invisible to
the majority of normal humans.
But we can see them fine?
Those with daemons
of their own to wield
are given the ability to see us.
We may also show ourselves
to individuals
of our own volition,
should the situation warrant it.
Furthermore,
there are some who simply have
the instinct to see us.
-[dog barks]
-[WOMAN] Huh?
What's gotten into you?
What does he think
he's barking at?
[YURU] The Kagemori clan,
was it?
Do they have daemons
of their own?
They do.
A few of them are wielders.
And how would you
describe them?
Like a huge pain in the ass.
They used to ally with us.
Now, they only live down here.
You can think of them
like a branch family
to Higashi Village.
They had some
ideological differences
they just weren't able
to get past.
You don't wanna get involved
with guys like that
if you don't have to.
We've got a whole bunch
of names of people we trust
written down
in our database.
Er, our list of people
with ties to the village.
For a while now,
we've heard rumors
from former village residents
that one of the twins was
in league with the Kagemoris.
Turns out they weren't
just rumors.
[panting]
[whimpering]
[footsteps]
-[AOI] Come on.
-[elevator dings]
Hurry up. Just close the door.
[whimpers]
Hey, baby.
Why you running from me?
[whimpers] No! Please,
would you just leave me alone?
You know we're long past that.
If I left you alone,
how would I ever kill you?
[AOI] Stay back.
-I'm warning you!
-[chuckles]
You'd better back up,
'cause if you get closer...
[STALKER] Huh?
[in demonic voice]
...then you...
-[stalker whimpers]
-...will be in my reach.
[Aoi chuckles]
-[monster growling]
-[stalker whimpers]
[JIN] Good evening, Miss Aoi.
This is Jin.
Regarding your stalker,
consider it handled.
[demonic voices moaning]
[JIN] He's never gonna come
near you again.
That much I can promise.
You're safe to return
to the office now.
On that note,
I'll notify your boss, too.
Pleasure working with you.
[monster growls]
[woman humming]
[metallic clank]
[elevator dings]
[WOMAN] Huh?
[monster growling]
[woman whimpers]
-[JIN] Hello there, miss.
-[woman gasps]
[monster growls]
I take it you're able
to see them?
[woman gasps]
[WOMAN] I...
Uh...
[Makoto grunts]
-[Makoto growls]
-[Jin shushes]
[JIN] It's our secret.
[DERA] To be perfectly honest,
Hana and I
aren't told much, either.
[HANA] Why would we be?
Our families have lived
down here for generations.
The job's a hand-me-down
from our ancestors.
[DERA] I had two orders.
Granny Yamaha told me
to keep outsiders
away from the village,
and to make sure you twins
didn't fall into enemy hands.
She was real insistent
about that one.
Otherwise, I supply goods
and relay info.
I try and do whatever odd jobs
crop up down here.
I've never actually been
to Higashi.
Frankly, it's not my place
to question what
the village elders think.
As a Tadera, I follow the rules
that've been passed down to me.
Oh, yeah.
My real name's
Ryu Tadera, by the way.
But you can still call me Dera.
In the keep,
Granny seemed terrified
by the idea the assailants
might take me.
She even told you
to get me out of there
instead of staying
to help fight.
So explain it to me.
Why are we special?
[RIGHT] They say
it can only happen
on the day of the equinox.
When a twin boy
and girl are born
on either side of the sunrise,
the world will be torn asunder.
To our knowledge,
the last of these twins
before you and your sister
were born
some 400 years ago.
Twins dividing night and day
were born inside
the same village.
In that era,
a war had split the nation
into east and west.
Years prior, another war
had already divided them
into north and south.
Daemon wielders were
manipulating behind the scenes
on both occasions.
What are you saying?
That we've both been cursed
to throw the world into chaos?
Nay. Those who wish
to abuse your powers
to their own ends
made these problems.
Our powers?
But I'm just a normal kid.
For now, yes.
[LEFT] If you would,
you have the right
to claim power.
And by the looks
of things back there,
Asa's already claimed it.
Indeed.
That was "Break." I'm sure.
[RIGHT] "Break."
It is the ability
to forcibly unravel all things.
Even the strongest of barriers
falls before it.
As easy as cracking an egg.
[LEFT] There's another
half of the pair, "Seal."
The power
to forcibly close all things.
As easy as shutting a door.
What happens if the two powers
collide with each other?
It'd be quite the paradox.
Have both the powers ever been
claimed at the same time?
As far as we are aware,
that is yet to occur.
[DERA] You heard her.
Means no one knows
how that disaster
would play out.
You think maybe all the rumors
have taken on a life
of their own?
Do the villagers
get what's going on?
Seems like a lot.
Good point.
I never knew about
the barrier around us, for one.
How did you manage
to get in and out of it, Dera?
There's a specific route
you have to take
to circumvent it.
Go counterclockwise
around these rocks
X amount of times.
Hang a right when you reach
this crossroad.
Turn around at the next
and go through the valley.
When you hit the big tree,
take a sharp ninety-degree turn.
Pain in the ass to remember.
The Tadera clan was trusted
with the route a long time ago,
so I'm able to pass through
the barrier
whenever I feel like it.
Your own mother's actually
a woman from down the mountain
who stumbled upon the path
during a long hike
by coincidence.
[DERA] It's not unheard of.
People wander when they're lost.
Some happen to wander
the right way.
[Nagisa grunts softly]
[bird cawing]
[NAGISA] Huh?
[Nagisa gasps]
[Nagisa pants]
[Yuru grunts softly]
[NAGISA] Yuru?
I was born and raised
in a place far away
from the village, you know.
And there,
your name means "night."
I would like to return someday.
I'll take you,
your father and sister
and show you where I grew up.
[Yuru chuckles softly]
[Nagisa chuckles]
♪
[birds chirping]
[beeping]
[YURU] Flush when you're done.
Make sure it goes down.
Wash your hands.
[Yuru grunts softly]
[YURU] I don't like these things
that roar like tiny dragons
were stuffed in them.
[YURU] Kill the lights
before leaving. Good.
There! I've learned
all the rules
to using the latrine
in this world.
Mm-hm.
[indistinct chatter, laughter]
[YURU] But still,
can you believe they don't have
to draw any water from a well?
And how come
pushin' those clicky things
makes lights appear
out of glass?
Speaking of light,
the city looks
positively radiant at night.
And the sheer number
of castles...
It's impressive, to be certain.
[RIGHT] How many lords
must they have
to require so many?
[YURU] They're not castles.
Apparently, they're homes.
Dera said dozens of people
can live in each one,
like a vertical town.
[LEFT] The population
of the capital is remarkable.
[YURU] No. It's not even
the capital!
He said the capital
is called "Tokyo,"
and there are
ten million people in it.
That's preposterous!
How do you harvest enough rice
for all of them?
There are people here
beyond what the eye can see!
Surely, we're in this "Tokyo!"
[YURU] Hold on, I know the name.
I'm sure I do.
Hana told it to me.
We're in Guntama.
Guntama, yes. I understand.
Well, we should find
no trouble hiding you
if these crowds are always
as large as these.
The forest is the best place
to hide a tree.
And in this forest of men,
you're hoping to find the tree
that is your sister. Yes?
Yeah.
Dera and Hana are kind.
They're probably safe.
Still, they have direct ties
to my deception.
To that false sister
and the villagers
who lied to me.
So I can't trust them
completely.
That said, I can't put
full faith in this girl
who calls herself Asa, either.
[children laughing]
[BOY] Can't catch me!
Fleeing the village with a child
was no small decision to make.
There's a reason.
I need to find my parents.
And to do that,
I'll capture this "Asa"
and have her take me.
If I may, I'd like your help.
We're looking for someone
in this world
where we don't know
our right from our left.
Sounds fun!
We haven't had
half as much intrigue in ages!
-Let's enjoy!
-You shouldn't be so raucous
with matters important
to our master, Right.
He's serious.
Then tell me how you're feeling
about it, Left! Do go on.
[LEFT] Hm.
I am not the hunted.
I much prefer to be the hunter.
-[Right chuckles]
-[YURU] Mmm-mmm, mm?
Yeah, sounds like a plan.
Good job
lockin' us down a place.
Hey, welcome back.
What's going on?
Hana just gave us the call
we've been waiting for.
Sounds like she found us
a new place to crash.
We can finally kiss
living in a car goodbye!
[YURU] Mm...
You said "call."
Is the call coming
from that thing?
What is it?
My phone?
Um...
Where do we even start
with something like this?
It's for sending letters
and voices like a signal fire.
No, that kind of makes it
sound dangerous.
Oh, well, that's about
the gist of it.
Aye, that makes sense.
It is for sending out
smoke signals.
[YURU] Understood.
[Dera chuckles]
[DERA]
They'll just believe anything.
The goofs.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
Let me introduce you.
This is Kotetsu and Jiro!
[YURU] Right! When you leave
the latrine, you...
[RIGHT] Kill the lights!
[all yelling]